

SHOON LEI PHYU (REI)

Saitama, Japan 🔒

+818091834964

shoonleiphyu97@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/reislp/ in







OBJECTIVE

Proactive youth innovator who is studying Digital Business and Innovation (Master) at Tokyo International University and I will be graduating in March 2024. I excel the skills of managing IT projects, website development and AI web applications development acquired from the knowledge of working 3 years in freelancing, the insurance industry, B2B IT consulting industries and AI consulting firm. I am currently looking for the AI Engineer/Consultant positions where I can utilize my Al Knowledge & Programming skills, Product Development and Project Management skills.



EXPERIENCE

Al Engineer (Internship)

Araya Inc., I Tokyo, JP

SEPTEMBER 2022 - PRESENT

Development of Computer Vision Al model using Python, JavaScript, and machine learning algorithms.

Skills: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Chrome Extension Development, ReactJS, Python

Executive – Digital Solution (Full-time) PRUDENTIAL MYANMAR LIFE INSURANCE CO. LTD., I Yangon, MM

JUNE 2020 - APRIL 2022

Tasks

- Acted as the product owner of developing features in the Pulse Al application using Agile Project Management Methodologies.
- Draw the user journeys as required using Figma.
- Coordinated in the implementation of Digital Payments & Partnerships with big financial institutions: KBZ pay, MPT pay, CB pay, OK dollar, 2C2P.
- Revise the SLAs, PLAs and Legal Contracts for Partnerships, Influencer Marketing and FinTech Partnerships together with Legal Department

Awards

- The Star Performer Award for the excellence in performance, communication, and team accomplishments
- Exceptional Effort Award in Pulse Al application given by CEO.

Skills: Al Project Management, IT Contract Review, Digital Partnerships, Digital Consulting, JIRA, Figma.

System/Web App Developer (Full-time)

FORVAL MYANMAR CO.LTD., I Yangon, MM

APRIL 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020

 Delivered ERP web applications for the B2B and B2C customers within specific timeframes using KINTONE platform and JavaScript, RESTful APIs. (Industries: telecommunication, agriculture, automobile, and HR.)

Skills: JavaScript, Backend Development.



EDUCATION

M.SC IN DIGITAL BUSINESS AND INNOVATION

TOKYO INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY I TOKYO, JAPAN

APRIL 2022 - PRESENT

Coursework: Entrepreneurship Strategy, Python Programming for Data Analysis, Al Product Development, Innovation Management, Implementation of Blockchain Technology with a project, New Product Development

Thesis: Patent Summarization with Conceptual Graph Extraction

Awards: Recipient of Monbukagakusho Scholarship for International Students in Japan 2022

Skills: Al product development, Project Management, Natural Language Processing, Deep Learning, Leadership, Blockchain.

LLM (COMMERCIAL LAWS)

UNIVERSITY OF YANGON I YANGON, MYANMAR

JANUARY 2019 - MARCH 2022

GPA: 4.5

Laws: Commercial Laws, Intellectual Property Laws, Taxation, Foreign Investments

Thesis: Legal Protection of Utility Model in Japan and Myanmar 2021

Activities: Best Basketball Player (Center Position) in 2022, Myanmar representative in JENESYS Cultural

Exchange program, finalist in business model proposal competition.

B.SC (Hons) BUSINESS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

UNIVERSITY OF GREENWICH I LONDON, UNITED KINGDOM

JUNE 2013 - FEBUARY 2017

Second Upper Degree

Coursework: Website Design and Development, Networking and IT Infra Security

Project: Point of Sales System of Ngwe Wathone Co. Ltd.,



SKILLS

Programming Languages

• Python, PHP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, ReactJS Framework

Technical Skills

- Web Application Development, Web Design and Development, Front-end Development
- Machine Learning & Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing, Computer Vision

Soft Skills

• solution-oriented, open-minded, responsible, good communication and negotiation

License

• Junior Law Practitioner in Myanmar, International Driving Permit issued by Myanmar Road Transport Administration Department.

Speaking Languages

• Burmese (Native), English (fluent), Japanese (JLPT N3)



OTHERS

Hobbies

- Basketball: Best Rebounder & Forward of 2020 in University of Yangon, Captain of UY in 2022
- Archery: Second Prize in Intra-Universities Championship in Yangon
- Badminton

Volunteering Experiences and Projects

- Freelance Website Developer: Building websites for celebrities.
- ProLab Myanmar Founder: Physical Education Awareness Startup in Myanmar, Youth Leadership and Youth Empowerment
- Legal Lifecycle Management Project Manager: In collaboration with KST Legal Law firm for the development of legal system.